In this portion of coverage of random methods,
we will look at randomizing as it relates
to words and phrases.
The first such method is the shuffle method,
which rearranges the order of a list.
In this 623-shuffle file, I am using the shuffle
method, shown on line 3, to arrange categories
for a quiz on the periodic table of the elements,
related to chemistry, which are stored in
a list named categories on line 2.
Notice the import on line 1 looks different
than the previous import statements on the
random module library.
Rather than import one element of the library,
we are importing the entire library so we
can use any module within the library.
I will run this code and we see the categories
in a different order, which would then dictate
the order of categories being asked about
for a chemistry quiz.
From shuffle, we move to the choice module
within the random library.
Choice, as you may have guessed from the name
of the module, chooses a value, at random,
from a list of values.
In this 623-choice file, we have the same
import statement on line 1 and the same categories
list on line 2.
However, the code on line 3 is different,
as the shuffle method has been replaced with
the choice method on the categories list.
Because we are extracting one value from the
list of categories, we are storing that choice
in a variable-named category.
Then, in line 5, we see a print statement
to print the random category chosen from the
categories list.
I will run this code, and indeed, each time
I run the code, we see one category randomly
chosen from the list of categories.
While a choice returns one random value from
a list, the sample method returns multiple
random values from a list.
Suppose we want to get two questions from
two categories within this list.
To return multiple random values from a list,
we will want to use the sample method instead
of the choice method.
On line 3, I will change the category variable
to random.sample, and then, in parentheses,
we need two arguments: the list and the number
of unique values to get from the list.
Thus, I will enter categories and then 2 for
the two needed arguments.
I will then run the code, and we get two categories
returned as a list.
One more point to make about sample versus
choice.
You could run the choice method twice here,
but there is no guarantee you will get two
unique values returned.
If you want, for example, to ensure a question
comes out of two different categories before
a category is repeated, use the sample method.
This topic concludes the domain and all the
exam topics in this course.
Like we did at the halfway point in this course,
it’s time for you to build a project from
the ground up.
Look over the Review 6.2 exercise in your
project workbook, and as you build your app,
keep in mind there is no single correct answer
for the scenario.
When you are done, come back to the videos,
and we will go through a possible answer for
the scenario.